Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Collection on Individuals WEB.ARC.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
Tamiment Library Web Collection on Individuals
2007-ongoing
WEB.ARC.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
72.0 websites
The Tamiment Library Web Collection on Individuals, first began by Tamiment in 2007, includes archived websites of individuals connected with the labor movement, trade unionism, radical politics, feminism, civil rights, social justice, prisoner rights, economic justice, radical art and music, alternative press, gay rights, anarchism, and peace and other movements. Website contain a variety of formats and materials, including pdfs, images, multimedia, event listings, blogs, and other web-based media.
Tamiment Library.
Historical/Biographical Note
Tamiment Library, New York University began web archiving in 2007 as part of a grant given by the National Digital Information Infrastructure and Preservation Program (NDIPP) of the Library of Congress. As most unions, left movements, progressive organizations, and others stop creating ephemeral material and paper based collections and move most of their administrative and informational material to the web, Tamiment continued to document the changing face of the labor and left movement into the web era. Tamiment uses the California Digital Library’s Web Archiving Service (WAS) as their tool to capture and preserve websites. WAS was created in 2007 and Tamiment is one of its earliest partners. The California Digital Library provides the storage and infrastructure for the project.
Related Archival Material
Tamiment Library Web Collection on Labor Unions
Tamiment Library Web Collection on Organizations
Printed Ephemera Collection on Individuals (PE 030)
Scope and Content Note
The Tamiment Library Web Collection on Individuals, first began by Tamiment in 2007, archives websites of individuals connected with the labor movement, trade unionism, radical politics, feminism, civil rights, social justice, prisoner rights, economic justice, radical art and music, alternative press, gay rights, anarchism, and peace and other movements. This is an assembled collection, websites are chosen by the archivists.
These websites contain a huge variety of media, which include videos, pdfs, blog postings (including Tumblr and Wordpress blogs), petitions, news feeds, audio, message boards, and other media. These websites often act to document and update upon the individuals’ activities, schedule upcoming events, build awareness of their causes or work, and information on projects the individuals are working on. Websites include writings and articles by individuals, examples of their work, or other activities.
The web collection documents the publicly available content of the web page, it does not archive material that is password protected or blocked due to robot txt exclusions. Although Tamiment attempts to archive the entirety of a website, certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. This can include videos (Youtube, Vimeo, or otherwise), pdfs (including Scribd or another pdf reader), rss feeds/plug-ins (including twitter), commenting platforms (disqus, facebook), presi, images, or anything that is not native to the site.
Arrangement
Websites are arranged alphabetically.
Access Restrictions
Archived websites are open to researchers without restrictions. Archived websites are made publically available 6 months after their initial capture.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. This can include videos (including Youtube and Vimeo), pdfs (including Scribd or another pdf reader), rss feeds/plug-ins (including Twitter), commenting platforms (disqus, Facebook), presi, images, or anything that is not native to the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Robot txt exclusions also change the formatting of websites from their original display, websites with robot txt exclusions often display as an index.
Keyword and file-type search are also available to archived websites through the Web Archiving Service (WAS). To search for keywords within archived websites, click a site name link in the container list. From that page, click the "search" tab on the top left corner. From the search page, you can search by keyword, URL, and file type across all captures of one site or all the sites in the project.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Websites are selected by archivists and captured through the use of the California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service (WAS). WAS uses a web crawler to copy the website at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy of the website.
Accruals note
In general, crawls of sites are added quarterly. New sites are added to finding aids upon completion of 6 month embargo.
Existence and Location of Originals note
Clicking on the links provided in the container list will take the user to the Web Archiving Service (WAS) page for the website. Sometimes the original website is still available on the live web and the original URL may be available. To get to the original web page, click the live link provided in the "Latest Starting URL" field on the WAS page.
Take Down Policy
Tamiment respects robot txt exclusions and requests from websites with robot txt exclusions to allow our crawler to capture their website. Tamiment will also honor the website owner’s request to remove their website from the collection. To request a site removal, please contact tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu
Abraham Lincoln Brigade.; Anarchists.; Artists |x Political activity.; Black nationalism |z United States.; Communists.; Legislators |z United States.; Political prisoners |z United States.; Prisoners |x Civil rights.; Radicals.; Reporters and reporting.; United States |x Politics and government.
- Abu-Jamal, Mumia (Freedom Journal) Archived Website, Sep 28, 2007 - Jan 22, 2009
  Scope and Contents note
  This website is the predecessor to http://www.freemumia.com/. Mumia Abu-Jamal (born Wesley Cook on April 24, 1954) was convicted and sentenced to death for the 1981 murder of Philadelphia police officer Daniel Faulkner. As of 2011, Abu-Jamal’s death sentence was declared unconstitutional, and the issue of sentencing was remanded a new hearing. This website was dedicated to preventing the execution of Abu-Jamal and securing a new trial for him.
  Abu-Jamal, Mumia; Abu-Jamal, Mumia |v Periodicals.; Black nationalism |z United States.; Political prisoners |z United States.
- Acoli, Sundiata Archived Website, May 4, 2012 - ongoing; Sundiata Acoli Freedom Campaign (SAFC).
  Sundiata Acoli (born in 1939, as Clark Edward Squire) is an African-American activist who was a member of the Black Panther Party (BPP) and Black Liberation Army (BLA). On May 2, 1973, he was involved in a shootout on the New Jersey turnpike, resulting in the death of a state trooper and BLA member Zayd Malik Shakur. He was convicted and is currently serving a life sentence in the federal penitentiary at Leavenworth, Kansas. This website is his support website to free Acoli.
  Acoli, Sundiata; Political prisoners.
- Bacon, David Archived Website, Aug 9, 2009 - ongoing; Bacon, David, 1948-
  David Bacon is photojournalist, labor organizer, and immigrant-rights activist, and author. The website contains photographs and articles by Bacon.
  Working class--Fiction.; Working class--Photographs.; Working class.
- Bailey, Bill (The Kid from Hoboken) Archived Website, Jul 3, 2012 - Jan 3, 2013; Bailey, Bill
  This website contains the Kid from Hoboken series, the autobiography of Bill Bailey (1911–1995). Bill Bailey was a veteran of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade and labor activist.
  Abraham Lincoln Brigade.; Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade.
- Baraka, Amiri Archived Website, Jul 11, 2012 - Jul 11, 2013; Baraka, Imamu Amiri, 1934-
  Amiri Baraka, born in 1934, in Newark, New Jersey, USA, is an activist and author of over 40 books of essays, poems, drama, and music history and criticism. He writes on topics ranging from racism, national oppression, colonialism, neo-colonialism, self-determination, and national and human liberation. The website contains a biography, books, multimedia, and writings.
  Black nationalism |z United States.
- Bonosky, Phillip Archived Website, Nov 10, 2010 - Dec 17, 2013; Bonosky, Phillip
  Phillip Bonosky (1916-2013) was a Lithuanian American; author and journalist; and longtime member and activist of the Communist Party USA. He was on the editorial board of Masses and Mainstream, and the cultural editor, and later Moscow correspondent of the Party's newspaper, the People’s Daily World. He was also on the editorial board of Political Affairs, the Party's monthly periodical. The web site includes his writings and a blog.
  Communists |z United States.; Lithuanian Americans.
- Bragg, Billy: Activism Archived Website, Dec 2, 2010 - ongoing; Bragg, Billy
  Stephen William Bragg (born 20 December 1957), known as Billy Bragg, is an English alternative rock musician and socialist left wing activist who blends elements of folk music, punk rock and protest songs, and his lyrics mostly deal with political or romantic themes. His music career has lasted more than 30 years, and he has collaborated with Natalie Merchant, Johnny Marr, Hank Wangford, Florence and the Machine, Kate Nash, Leon Rosselson, members of R.E.M., Michelle Shocked, Less Than Jake, Kitty Daisy and Lewis, Kirsty MacColl, and Wilco. Bragg often plays and speaks at the Tolpuddle Martyrs festival. This website is his official homepage and features his activist campaigns.
  Composers; Lyricists; Political ballads and songs; Socialists |z Great Britain.
- Bravo, Estela Archived Website, Apr 4, 2014-ongoing; Bravo, Estela
  Scope and Content Note
  Estela Bravo is a documentary filmmaker, working since the 1980s. Her work focuses on Latin America, especially Cuba She is known for her films "Ninos Desparecidos," "Holy Father and Gloria," "After the Battle," "Returning to Chile," "Maurice," "Fidel," "Who Am I? The Found Children of Argentina," and "Children in Debt." The website contains information on her films, especially her film, "Operation Peter Pan," film reviews, and her biography.
  Documentary films.; Independent filmmakers.
- Chambers, Whittaker Archived Website, Jul 15, 2011 - ongoing; Chambers, Whittaker
  This site is the official website of Whittaker Chambers (1901-1961). He was a member of the Workers Party of America (1925), journalist at the Daily Worker and New Masses (1926- 1932), Soviet underground agent (1932- 1938), editor and senior editor at TIME magazine (1939- 1948), witness in the Alger Hiss Case (1948-1950), author of best-selling memoir Witness (1952), member of the founding editors of National Review, and (posthumous) recipient of the Presidential Medal of Freedom. This website contains blog posts related to the lives of other communists, information about the life of Chambers, and posting on current events related to Chambers’ work.
  Hiss, Alger; Communists |z United States.; Espionage, Soviet |z United States.
- Chomsky, Noam Archived Website, Sep 23, 2007 - ongoing; Chomsky, Noam.
  Noam Chomsky (b. 1928) is a prominent linguistics scholar and prolific anarchist writer and political activist. This website was originally created by Pablo Stafforini, with the purpose of celebrating Chomsky's work and encouraging activism worldwide. In December 2003, it became Noam Chomsky's official website, documenting his political activity and writings.
  Anarchists |z United States.
- Colichman, Paul Archived Website, Apr 20, 2012 - ongoing; Colichman, Paul
  This is the official blog of Paul Colichman, CEO of HearMedia, a public media and entertainment company exclusively targeting the lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender (LGBT) demographic, formed in 2008. The website contains his blog and links to his other websites, including the Advocate, AlysonBooks, Out, Gay.com, here!, and SheWired.
  Sexual minorities.
- Conway, Eddie Archived Website, May 6, 2012 - ongoing; Conway, Eddie
  Marshall Eddie Conway (born April 23, 1946) was the Minister of Defense of the Baltimore chapter of the Black Panther Party, charged with the murder a Baltimore police officer in 1970. Conway is currently serving a life sentence at the Jessup Correctional Institution. Conway claims to be a "political prisoner" and claims innocence. He was targeted by the FBI's COINTELPRO (Counter Intelligence Program), which operated against and infiltrated anti-war and Civil Rights groups. The website is run by the Partnership for Social Justice, which works to free Conway and on other social justice projects in Baltimore.
  Political prisoners.
- Davidson, Carl Archived Website, Jul 8, 2011 - ongoing; Davidson, Carl
  Keep on Keepin' On is the blog of Carl Davidson, a former student leader of the new left of the 1960s, who served as a Vice President and National Secretary of Students for a Democratic Society. Currently he is a national co- chair of the Committees of Correspondence for Democracy and Socialism and a national board member of Solidarity Economy Network, advocating a mixture of market socialism and worker ownership. Recently Davidson led Progressives for Obama, now called Progressive America Rising, as an independent left- progressive initiative, in part to convince those on the radical left to pursue what he considers more pragmatic alternatives. He has also worked on a leadership level with United for Peace and Justice and its local affiliates. The website contains blog posts with analysis on contemporary politics.
  Socialists |z United States.
- Dawkins, Richard Archived Website, Apr 15, 2013 - ongoing; Dawkins, Richard
  The Richard Dawkins Foundation for Reason and Science works to support scientific education, critical thinking and evidence-based understanding of the natural world to overcome religious fundamentalism, superstition, intolerance and suffering. Richard Dawkins is an English ethologist, evolutionary biologist, and author. The website contains videos from speaking events and conferences, articles, news, and other multimedia.
- Dead Anarchists Archived Website, Jul 14, 2012 - ongoing; Dead Anarchists
  Dead Anarchists features the essays, writings, and obituaries on deceased anarchists.
  Anarchists.
- Deck, Andy (Andyland Art and Activism) Archived Website, Jul 21, 2010 - ongoing; Deck, Andy
  The website, and related sites of political artist Andy Deck, includes artwork and political commentary, much of which is concerned with digital and/or online art and resources for activists.
  Art |x Political aspects.; Digital art |z United States.
- FeministaJones.com Archived Website, Aug 21, 2014-ongoing; Jones, Feminista
  Feminista Jones is a mental health social worker, sex-positive feminist writer, public speaker, and community activist from New York City. Feminista has been featured in several online publications, notably as a contributor to Salon.com and TIME.com, and she has been syndicated in TheRoot.com and TheGriot.com. For two years, she hosted a sex-positive feminist podcast called This Week In Blackness: After Dark, which discussed topics related to sex and sexuality, race, and feminism. In 2013, Feminista was selected as a United Nations Foundation Fellow for her dynamic social media influence. In 2014, she launched a global anti-street harassment campaign (#YouOKSis) and a National Moment of Silence protesting police brutality (#NMOS14), both of which received international media attention. For this work, she was awarded the 2014 Black Weblog Award for Outstanding Online Activism. The website contains her blog; information on events, appearances, and speaking engagements; publications; videos and other media.
  African American feminists.; Internet and activism.
- Franken, Al Archived Website, Mar 8, 2012 - ongoing; Franken, Al
  Al Franken (born May 21, 1951) is currently the junior United States Senator from Minnesota. He is a member of the Minnesota Democratic-Farmer-Labor Party, which affiliates with the national Democratic Party. Franken achieved note as a writer and performer for the television show Saturday Night Live from its conception in 1975 before moving to writing and acting in films and television shows. He then became a political commentator, author of five books and host of a nationally syndicated radio show on the Air America Radio network. The website is his official website and contains a blog.
  Legislators |z United States |v Biography.
- Free Mumia Abu-Jamal Coalition, NYC Archived Website, Dec 23, 2008 - ongoing; Free Mumia Abu-Jamal Coalition, NYC.
  Mumia Abu-Jamal (born Wesley Cook on April 24, 1954) was convicted and sentenced to death for the 1981 murder of Philadelphia police officer Daniel Faulkner. Prior to arrest, Abu-Jamal was a Black Panther Activist and radio journalist. Since his conviction, his case has received international attention and he has become a controversial cultural icon. Supporters and opponents disagree on the appropriateness of the death penalty, whether he is guilty, or whether he received a fair trial. During his imprisonment he has published several books and other commentaries, notably Live from Death Row. As of 2011, Abu-Jamal’s death sentence was declared unconstitutional, and the issue of sentencing was remanded a new hearing. FreeMumia.com serves as the official website of the Free Mumia Abu-Jamal Coalition (NYC) and the International Concerned Family and Friends of Mumia Abu-Jamal (ICFFMAJ), which forms the Free Mumia Abu-Jamal Coalition (NYC), a group of individuals and organizations in New York organizing for the freedom of Mumia Abu-Jamal.
  Abu-Jamal, Mumia; Black nationalism |z United States.; Political prisoners |z United States.
- Geoghegan, Tom Archived Website, Nov 9, 2011 - Feb 8, 2014; Geoghegan, Thomas
  Thomas Geoghegan (b. 1949, Cincinnati, Ohio) is an American labor lawyer and author based in Chicago. Geoghegan has represented the United Mine Workers, Teamsters for a Democratic Union, and currently works at Despres, Schwartz and Geoghegan Ltd. Tom has filed suits in a wide variety of public interest, labor, and employment law cases. He has represented individuals discriminated against in the workplace due to their race, sex, disability, age or sexual orientation, and he has sued employers who violated sexual harassment laws and the Family and Medical Leave Act. He has also filed lawsuits to enforce child labor laws, expand voting rights, crack down on the payday loan industry, and require public health measures to stop the spread of tuberculosis among the homeless. Geoghegan was also a Democratic candidate for Rahm Emanuel's seat in Illinois's 5th congressional district special election, 2009. He lost to Mike Quigley. He writes articles for major publications on current events issues from a political left standpoint.
  Lawyers |x Political activity |z United States.
- Graham, Robert Archived Website, Jun 6, 2011 - ongoing; Graham, Robert
  Robert Graham’s Anarchy weblog is an additional commentary and selections to accompany Robert Graham’s anthology of anarchist writings, entitled Anarchism: A Documentary History of Anarchist Ideas. Material from a variety of regions, movements, and intellectual currents, from the Daoists in ancient China, to the Diggers in the English Revolution, the enragés in the French Revolution, various European anarchist currents, such as the anarchist communists, the anarcho- syndicalists and the Platformists, the "pure" and class struggle anarchists in Japan, Korean revolutionaries, the Chinese anarchist movement, Latin American anarchists, anarchist feminists, libertarian pedagogues, anarchist artists and writers, Russian anarchists, North American anarchists and the Spanish libertarian movement, including translations and out of print sources.
  Anarchism.; Libertarianism.
- Guthrie, Woody (1912-1967) Archived Website, Aug 16, 2009 - ongoing; Guthrie, Woody, 1912-1967.
  The Official Woody Guthrie Website is also the home of the Woody Guthrie Archives, the Woody Guthrie Foundation, and Woody Guthrie Publications, Inc. Woody Guthrie (1912-1967) was a famous American folk singer, and Communist, best known for the anthem "This Land is Your Land."
  Communists |z United States.; Folk singers |z United States.
- Halleck, DeeDee Archived Website, Oct 28, 2011 - ongoing; Halleck, DeeDee
  DeeDee Halleck (born January 5, 1940) is a media activist, founder of Paper Tiger Television and co-founder of the Deep Dish Satellite Network, the first grass roots community television network. She is Professor Emerita in the Department of Communication at the University of California, San Diego. Note: Tamiment Library is getting her personal papers.
  Direct broadcast satellite television.; Documentary films.; Television broadcasting.
- Hanisch, Carol Archived Website, Dec 9, 2011 - Mar 6, 2013; Hanisch, Carol
  Carol Hanisch is a radical feminism and a member of New York Radical Women and Redstockings. She was a founding member of New York Radical Women in 1967, an originator of the Miss America Protest, and an editor of the Redstocking's book, Feminist Revolution (1973) and the journal Meeting Ground from 1978 - 1992. This website contains her articles, songs, and speeches, including her most famous work, The Personal is Political (1969).
  Feminists |z United States.
- Hartmann, Thom (Thom Hartmann Program) Archived Website, Apr 26, 2012 - ongoing; Hartmann, Thom, 1951-
  The Thom Hartmann Program is a nationally syndicated progressive talk program (broadcast both on radio and television), first broadcast in 2003. The show is hosted by Thom Hartmann (b. 1951). The website contains information on his talk show, his blog, newsletter, podcast, forum, and store.
  Alternative radio broadcasting.
- Hashmi, Syed (Fahad) Archived Website, Sep 15, 2010 - Dec 14, 2012; Hashmi, Syed
  Syed Hashmi, also known as Fahad, was born in Karachi, Pakistan in 1980 and immigrated to the United States with his family at the age of three. After receiving his masters in international relations in 2006 at the London Metropolitan University in England, he was arrested in London and extradited to the United States, charged with aiding Al Qaeda and other terrorism charges. In 2010, Hashmi plead guilty to some of the charges, and is currently serving a fifteen year sentence. FreeFahad.com works to free Hashmi, raises of awareness of the poor conditions of Hashmi’s imprisonment, including being subject to Special Administrative Measures (SAMs), and also advocate that he was arrested because he was outspoken against U.S. policies in the Middle East.
  Arab Americans |x Civil rights.; Political prisoners |z United States.; Solitary confinement |z United States.
- Hay, Harry Archived Website, Jul 31, 2009 - ongoing; Hay, Harry.
  The website is the official page of the film, "Hope Along the Wind: The Life of Harry Hay." Harry Hay (1912 –2002) was a labor advocate, onetime Communist Party member, and early leader in the American LGBT rights movement. He is known for his roles in helping to found several gay organizations, including the Mattachine Society, the first sustained gay rights group in the United States. The website gives information on the filmmakers, the making of the films, reviews and awards, and funders. The website also contains a transcript of the film.
  Communists |z United States.; Gay rights |z United States.
- Hayden, Tom Archived Website, Aug 20, 2010 - ongoing; Hayden, Tom